A picture as sensational as its subject!
Five Star Final is a crime, drama film directed by Mervyn LeRoy.
Searching for headlines at any cost, an unscrupulous newspaper owner forces his editor
to print a serial based on a past murder, tormenting a woman involved.
Joseph W. Randall, played by Edward G. Robinson.
Jenny Townsend, played by Marian Marsh.
Michael Townsend, played by H.B. Warner.
Phillip Weeks, played by Anthony Bushell.
Ziggie Feinstein, played by George E. Stone.
Nancy (Voorhees) Townsend, played by Frances Starr.
Five Star Final is a 1931 American pre-Code drama film about the excesses of
tabloid journalism directed by Mervyn LeRoy and starring Edward G.
Robinson, Aline MacMahon (in her screen debut) and Boris Karloff.
The screenplay was by Robert Lord and Byron Morgan based on the
1930 play of the same name by Louis Weitzenkorn.
The title refers to the practice of newspapers publishing a series of editions throughout the day, with their final-edition front page having five stars
printed and the word "Final." "Five Star Final" is also a font introduced during World War I and then favored by newspapers for its narrow type.
Warner Bros.
remade the film in 1936 as Two Against the World, also known as One Fatal Hour, starring Humphrey
Bogart in Robinson's part and set in a radio station instead of at a newspaper.
The film was nominated at the 5th Academy Awards (1931/1932)
for Best Picture, but lost to Grand Hotel.
Newspaper publisher William Randolph Hearst was greatly offended by the film, which
he interpreted as a thinly veiled attack on him and his operation.
He retaliated by publishing negative reviews in his papers
and pressuring theaters not to show the film.
The film explores themes of press, based on play or musical,
newspaper man, newspaper editor, pre-code.
The tone is emotional.